resume.md 7/29/2022

Dan Edens

(469)-636-7704

#### DanEdens31@gmail.com

Self Sufficient and Driven Software Engineer with a focus on Process Automation and Data Collection.

I Offer a wide range of experience in DevOps Project management, Data collection, Risk mitigation, and Compliance documentation.

Hands-on field experience spent ensuring data flow from sensors and assisting clients with data utilisation, yielded a strong practical sense for user-centred Design.

Experienced Operating Independently, and worked as a stand-alone remote branch for 3.5 years.

Incomprehensive list of tools I have delivered products using:

- Python, NodeJS, Javascript, Java, Visual Basic, HTML, REST, PHP, SQL, MQTT, and a variety of APIs
- DevOps CI/CD, Containerization, and Documentation generation
- Cloud platforms including Azure, Gitlab, AWS, and self-hosted services

## **Project Portfolio**

# Work History

#### Geo-Instruments

06/2018 - Present (07/2022)

VIdeo detailing what we do at Geo-instruments

Geotechnical Monitoring specialist responsible for managing projects including Data collection, Web development, Risk mitigation and Compliance documentation for a variety of industries.

- Managed multiple projects with job sites across the Midwest.
- Built backends for data collection and set up project Websites using Python, Javascript, NodeJS, MQTT,
   SQL, and PHP.
- Developed tools to improve efficiency and Issue response time.
- Experience with Data acquisition tools such as Solar controllers, Modems, Sensors, and dataloggers.

In addition to this Project management role, I heavily engaged myself in our Apps and Software departments.

Some of these duties include:

- 1. Setting up Customer websites
- 2. Automating data collection of field sensors
- 3. Alert Investigation
- 4. Setting up and maintaining reports to clients

resume.md 7/29/2022

4570 TX-121, Lewisville, TX 75056 - (214) 494-6341

Prep Cook: 01/2016 to 06/2018

- 1. Motivated food industry worker offering over 5 years of experience.
- 2. Lead Prep team, Maintained a show-ready kitchen for Chili's Test location
- 3. Took part in Franchise showcases and assisted in Marketing events such as filming TV commercials.
- 4. Worked closely with corporate offices to help field test timely and effective ways to improve menu recipes and standards.
- 5. Created a hands-free Recipe app for the kitchen's tablet.
- 6. Created Cooling log and Inventory tracking app.
- 7. Collected data on the accuracy of daily On-hand food quantities for a 6-month period. This Resulted in Improved Daily prep list efficiency.

#### Chili's Grill and Bar

190 Williamson Blvd, Ormond Beach, FL 32174 - (386) 672-7760

Prep Cook: 06/2014 to 09/2015

### Wood (Previously known as AMEC Earth & Environmental)

4490 Beltway Drive, Addison, TX 75001 - (469) 828-4100 Laboratory Technician 08/2013 to 03/2014

- 1. Performed laboratory testing on concrete and soil samples.
- 2. Collected and maintained data reports detailing project samples.
- 3. Managed test scheduling and preserving samples in limestone storage tanks
- Certifications:

**ACI Concrete Technicain certification** 

### Education

Associate of Arts: Computer Science

North Lake College - Irving, TX: 2012-2014

Focused on coursework in Mathematics and Intro to C++